# Blake Michalzik

bmichalzik@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/blakemichazik



+(1) 778 512 6850



https://blakerunner.com

### **Summary**

Hello, I'm Blake Michalzik

Soon to be grad with a Diploma in Computer Systems Technology from BCIT (Dec 2021)

An Australian/Canadian, with a passion for creation and problem solving for anything that can be solved with tech for your business.

With 10 years of Australian Military experience, I've learned a lot about how to deal with problems with deadlines, how to prioritize solutions and how to do that as a team.

Being around computers all my life and coming from a career where creative problem solving is a requirement, a natural progression has led me into computer engineering.

The intense learning conditions in BCIT's programs have really ignited my vision of what I can do within the tech industry. I've thoroughly enjoyed every minute of being a programmer and I look forward to applying what I've learned to business solutions.

I am still drawn to the concept of providing service. My goal is to leverage technology in a way to benefits humanity, and I am very excited to be on this path.

In my free time, you can find me in the gym listening to podcasts, in the kitchen whipping up a feast, watching mind-bending films or in a local forest enjoying the fresh air checking out what type of mushroom this one is up ahead.

I excel in group working environments with my experiences in the military called for professionalism always and the objective comes first. I am excellent at cutting down the issue and finding the core problem that needs to be solved. I have the tenacity that if I don't know now how to do something, I find the questions that need to be asked, and then find answers to them.

# **Experience**

# **Solutions Architect**

Pacific Eye Doctors

Jun 2020 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

- Research, develop and implement technical solutions for Pacific Eye Doctors.
- Ideated, Pitched, Implemented, Maintain, and update Pacific Eye Doctors' internal Information Portal for business standard operation practices, significantly improving new hire training times and creating a reliable reference source.
- Consult for business solutions involving SaaS, PaaS, and IaaS.



#### Setu Technologies Inc

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021 (4 months)

- Headed a team of 5 developers in Ideating, Designing, Developing, and Deploying a Web Application in 12 Weeks.
- Created a Web Application that provided a UI for Clients to view large amounts of time-series data from sensors monitoring business assets.
- Met MVP requirements in 8 weeks, allowing for additional data security implementation and administrative features.
- Personally responsible for Node RESTful API handling all server and database implementation.
- Maintained Cloud services and implemented CI/CD. Allowing for product uptime while fortnightly versions rolled out from a 2-week Sprint cycle.



### Developer

#### Al for Al

Apr 2021 - May 2021 (2 months)

- Headed a team of 4 in Ideating, Designing, Developing, and Deploying an Application in 5 weeks as a trial project for a 115 billion-dollar company.
- Created a Web application that provided a secure method for clients to view specific industry asset information as a dashboard with integrated ML predictive asset degradation rates.
- Provided a highly secure environment utilizing HTTPS, JWT, Azure ID to ensure the Power BI dashboard is only accessible by a specified user.
- Managed a large cloud network to integrate ML containers, MySQL database, Web Application Server, and Power Bi.



#### THE Server

#### The Keg Steakhouse + Bar

May 2019 - Mar 2020 (11 months)

- Provided a safe, friendly atomosphere for customer satisfaction.
- Developed active listening and body language tells to ensure specifics of customer orders are delivered to their needs.
- Adapted service to circumstances, eg sight or mobility-impaired.
- Developed by the minute prioritization of duties, dealing with high demand and deadlines.
- Provided high attention to detail with client product, preferences, and standards.



### Aircraft Maintenance Engineer - Avionics

#### Australian Army

Jan 2015 - Aug 2018 (3 years 8 months)

Role as an Avionics Technician, providing efficient maintenance and troubleshooting in a highly demanding environment. Responsible for the airworthiness of aircraft and fault rectification on the S70A-9 Black Hawk airframe.

- Delivered day and night shift maintenance, with limited resources and time while ensuring the airworthiness of \$32M Black Hawk helicopters
- Carried out servicing, overhauls, and repairs to aircraft electrical systems and equipment
- Identified and investigated defects, either providing on-the-spot repairs or recommended remedial follow-up actions.
- Improved the reliability of shift handovers by creating a paired handover methodology.

- Integrated with members of flight crew during test flights, providing expertise in diagnosing and rectifying aircraft faults



#### Section Commander

#### **Australian Army**

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Role as a Section Commander, managing and leading 12 personal on daily tasks, advising management, and contracted out as an expert.

- Responsible for 12 personnel, a heavy leadership role providing guidance, knowledge, mentorship, and command.
- Saw my team through a 150m minefield, providing safe passage for 300+ servicemen and \$125M+ of machinery
- Providing daily reports and feedback to management on training, personnel, and equipment.
- Provided extensively detailed reports on demolition objectives with plans, executions, and fail-safes.
- Developed personal readiness to deploy within 48 hours to anywhere in the world.



#### 🌦 Troop Recon Specialist

### **Australian Army**

Jan 2013 - Jan 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Role as a Combat Engineer Recon Specialist, providing specialist objective research to management for project outcomes.

- Led reconnaissance team to allow safe passage ahead for 200+ servicemen and \$100M+ worth of equipment
- Delivered detailed research on objectives, liaised with management, provided information, allowing them to meet their own objectives.
- Worked often alone or with one other in the field providing reporting.
- Developed use of clear, concise information via radio communications for reporting and findings.
- Liaised with other company supervisors with information that significantly shapes project outcomes.
- Developed personal readiness to deploy within 48 hours to anywhere in the world.



#### Combat Engineer

#### Australian Army

Apr 2008 - Jan 2013 (4 years 10 months)

Role as a Combat Engineer, providing specialist maneuver support to facilitate associated companies.

- Immediately qualified and selected for the specialist, 21st Troop Airborne Engineers.
- Airborne inserted into a multitude of joint company exercises providing close Engineer support.
- Constructed a multitude of temporary roads, fords, and structures.
- Erected semi-permanent bridges using both equipment and non-equipment components.
- Developed a personal trust, in Laying, arming, neutralizing, disarm and removing mines, booby traps, and improvised explosives.
- Operated medium rigid vehicles, small plant equipment, and small water vehicles.

#### **Education**

# BCIT British Columbia Institute of Technology

Diploma, Computer Science

2020 - 2022

- Cloud Option (AWS Services) DevOps, Serverless Computing, and Microservices
- OOP 1&2 (Java, Python)
- Web development 1&2, Internet Software Architecture (JS, HTML, CSS, Node, RESTful API, MongoDB)
- Intro to data communications
- Relational databases (MySQL)
- Algorithm analysis and design (Java)
- Android mobile development (Android, Java, Flutter, Firebase)
- Applied Probability and statistics
- Operating systems (C)
- Computer architecture
- Discrete mathematics
- Business communications
- Business analysis and system design

# RMIT University

Certificate IV of Aeroskills (Avionics), Aeronautics/Aviation/Aerospace Science and Technology, General

2015 - 2016

# Kelmscott Senior High School

High School 2001 - 2006

### **Licenses & Certifications**



Certificate IV in Aeroskills (Avionics) - Royal Australian Air Force

#### **Skills**

Military • Leadership • Teamwork • Explosives • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Agile Application Development • SQL • NoSQL • Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript